

Abdullah Munir

Date of birth: 09/03/1999

Nationality: Pakistani

Gender: Male

CONTACT

Gulstan e johar block 11
house c424 bangu gabol goth
kamran churangi
75290 Karachi, Pakistan
(Home)

abdullahmalik9x@gmail.com

(+92) 3120258744

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ abdullah-munir-a7b725190/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ abdullah-munir-a7b725190/

ABOUT MF

Cyber Security Engineer with a demonstrated history of working 3 years in the Cyber Security industry. Skilled in Ethical Hacking, Web Applications, Information Security, Penetration Testing, and Vulnerability Assessment. Strong information technology professional who has certification of CEH (Certified Ethical Hacking) and aspiring student of OSCP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/10/2023 - CURRENT Kyiv, Ukraine

SecOps Engineer Pakurity

- **Cloud IDS managing,** monitoring Falco IDS logs, and creation of custom rules in Kubernetes, Falco Deployments.
- **Website Security:** Implemented multi-layered security for the website. Audited, rectified misconfigurations, and added encryption.
- Mobile App Security: Conducted security assessments for iOS and Android apps. Identified vulnerabilities, and implemented measures for data protection according to OWASP top 10 best practices.
- **API Security:** Improved API security, identified attack vectors, and ensured secure functionality.
- **Cyber Security Awareness Trainings:** Secure code training for employees, best practices for securing their endpoint devices, and Advisories making for allowed secured apps and platforms.
- End Point Security Solutions: SentineONE endpoint security solution handling for all the employees, anomalies and threat detection

01/09/2022 - 09/2023 Karachi, Pakistan

Cyber Security Engineer Ezhire Pvt Limited

My primary areas of expertise included iOS and Android app security, API security, website security, cloud server security, implementation of cyber security policies, and driving security awareness among employees.

- **Website Security:** Implemented multi-layered security for the website. Audited, rectified misconfigurations, and added encryption.
- Mobile App Security: Conducted security assessments for iOS and Android apps. Identified vulnerabilities, implemented measures for data protection.
- **API Security:** Improved API security, identified attack vectors, and ensured secure functionality.
- **Cyber Security Policies:** Developed comprehensive policies following industry standards.
- **Employee Security Awareness:** Enhanced security culture via engaging programs, training, and materials.Incident Response:
- Collaborated across teams for effective incident management.

21/06/2021 - 15/08/2022 Karachi, Pakistan

Cyber Security Engineer Sybrid Pvt Limited

- Led penetration tests for critical applications and network infrastructure following OWASP, NIST, and CREST standards.
- Conducted thorough vulnerability assessments, identified gaps, and provided actionable risk mitigation suggestions.
- Collaborated with devs to implement fixes and retest after vulnerability remediation.
- Managed SOC operations: monitored alerts, investigated incidents, and coordinated responses.

- Developed/maintained incident response playbooks for consistent, effective reactions.
- Prepared detailed reports on penetration test findings and SOC activities, conveying technical insights to stakeholders.

01/05/2019 - 01/06/2019 Karachi, Pakistan

Web Application Security Researcher at Digital Freaks(internee)

1. Finding vulnerabilities in all the web applications through manually and through some tools scanning

01/01/2021 - 01/03/2021 Karachi, Pakistan

Black Box Tester(Internee) Technologia Solutions

1. Finding vulnerabilities in all the web applications through manually and through some tools scanning

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/05/2017 - 06/06/2021 Karachi, Pakistan

Bachelors of Software Engineering Bahria University Karachi Camous

Address Karachi, Pakistan, 75290, Karachi, Pakistan

CERTIFICATIONS

09/09/2022 - CURRENT

Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH Practical)

EC Council Certified Ethical Hacker , solved 20 practical questions with ethical hacking techniques, This course helps you master an ethical hacking methodology that can be used in penetration testing to lawfully assess the security of a system. This course delivers in-demand ethical hacking skills while preparing you for the internationally-recognized Certified Ethical Hacker certification exam from EC-Council.

13/09/2023 - CURRENT

Certified AppSec Practitioner

CAP is intended to be taken by application security engineers, application developers, SOC analysts, penetration testers, red and blue team members and any appsec enthusiast, who wants to evaluate and advance their knowledge.

Certificate ID: 7886939 Firstname: Abdullah

You can verify on the link given below

Link https://secops.group/certificate-validation/

12/09/2023 - CURRENT

Certified Cloud Security Practitioner - AWS (CCSP-AWS)

CCSP-AWS is intended to be taken by security engineers, security analysts, solution architects, cloud solution developers, threat analysts, penetration testers, red and blue team members and any security enthusiast, with a strong knowledge in the area of cloud security who wants to evaluate and advance their knowledge.

Certificate ID: 7881910 First Name: Abdullah

Link https://secops.group/certificate-validation/

- Practical Ethical Hacking By TCM
- Mobile Application Penetration Testing By TCM
 - API Security Testing Guide By The XSS Rat
 - **Android Application Hacking For Penetration Testing and Hacking**

DIGITAL SKILLS

NIST 800-82 | ethical hacking | White Hat Hacking | Vulnerability Assessment | VAPT Offensive Side | Owasp 10 | Python | Linux Kali Metasploit OSINT e Pentest | bug-reporting | Linux | exploit development | Linux (Red Hat, Debian) | cyber security managment | Cyber Security (Cryptography, IDS, HIDS, NAC, DLP e SIEM) | Cloud security | WEB APP PENETRATION TESTING | Mobile application penetration testing | Security awareness training & Security training for seafarers with designated security duties

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Urdu

Other language(s):

English

Listening B1 **Reading** B2

Spoken production B2 Spoken interaction B1

Writing B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

HALL OF FAME (FOR SECURING MULTIPLE WEBSITES)

- HOF on website for Reporting multiple bugs for (Accuneter.com)
 - Link Accuneter.com
- HOF on Stratistiot.com For Reporting IDOR

Link Stratistiot.com

HOF on thethingsnetwork.org For Reporting SSRF Link thethingsnetwork.org

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Bug Bounty Hunting

Bug bounty hunting on all over the internet, helped lot of organizations for securing there business websites by reporting major vulnerabilities in there websites and mobile apps